Guide to the Elmer Eric E. E. Schattschneider Papers, 1901 - 1971 (bulk 1955-1971)
Elmer Eric "E. E." Schattschneider Papers, 1901 - 1971 (bulk 1955-1971)
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - T-Un (Folder 37)
    - Taylor, George R., 1952
    - Teachers Insurance and Annuity Association of America, 1936
    - Thompson, Kenneth W., 1953-1954
    - Thomson, John S., 1949
    - Tierney, James F., 1953
    - Tillett, Paul, 1950-1954
    - Trager, Bernard H., 1969
    - Travelers Broadcasting Service Corporation, 1953
    - Truman, David B., 1947-1950
    - Truman, Harry S., 1957
    - Harry S. Truman Library, 1957
    - Truman, Tom, 1968
    - Tufts College, 1953
    - Turner, Henry A., 1952-1954
    - Tyler, Gus, 1953
    - Underwood, Kenneth, 1950-1954 Enc.
      Includes correspondence regarding the publication of the American Political Science Association Statement on party government published in Social Action.
    - United Automobile Workers, 1945
    - United Nations, 1954, 1964 Enc.
    - United States, Attorney General, 1949
    - United States, Civil Service Commission, 1965
    - United States, Council of Economic Advisors, 1949
  - Un (Folder 38)
    - United States, Department of Defense, U. S. Army Strategic Intelligence School, 1961-1962 Enc.
    - United States, Department of Defense, Industrial College of the Armed Forces, 1960-1961 Enc.
    - United States, Department of Defense, National War College, 1958-1961
      Includes typescript of Schattschneider's lecture, The U. S. Party System and National Security Policy (1961).
  - Un-Up (Folder 39)
    - United States, Department of the Interior, 1952
    - United States, Department of State, 1950-1952
    - United States Information Agency, 1965
    - United States, Library of Congress, 1945
    - United States, Office of the U. S. High Commissioner for Germany, 1951
    - United States, Selective Service System, 1944
    - United States Senate, Committee on Expenditures in the Executive Departments, 1951
    - United States Senate, Committee on Rules and Administration, 1951
    - University Center in Georgia, 1954 Enc.
    - Upholsterers’ International Union, 1948-1951 Enc.
  - Vanderbilt, Arthur T., 1948-1953 (Folder 40)
    Includes correspondence relating to the construction of the Public Affairs Center at Wesleyan.
  - Va-We (Folder 41)
    - Van Derhoof, Jack, 1953
    - Van Metre, Horace, 1931
    - Van Toor, James, circa late 1940s
    - University of Vermont, 1952-1953
    - Vines, Kenneth N., 1949 Enc.
    - Vose, Clement E., 1969
    - Wabash College, 1953
    - Wahlke, John, 1953
    - Wait, Robert, 1953
    - Wallace, Robert A., 1957
    - Wallace, Schuyler C., 1937-1955
    - Warbury, Coleman, 1953
    - Washington Post, 1963
    - Washington University, 1953
    - University of Washington, 1951
    - Wayne University, 1948-1954 Enc.
    - Webb, Harold, 1954
    - Weber, Wolfgang Hirsch, 1968-1969
  - We (Folder 42)
    - Wellesley College, 1952-1953
    - Wesleyan University, 1936-1967
    - Wesleyan University, Alumni Association of Washington, D. C., 1953
    - Wesleyan University, Alumni Council, 1969
    - Wesleyan University, Alpha Chi Rho, 1950
    - Wesleyan University, Philadelphia Alumni Association, 1950
    - West, W. Reed, 1944
    - Western Electric Company, 1961-1962 Enc.
    - Western Political Quarterly, 1951
    - Western Political Science Association, 1948
    - Westmeyer, Troy R., 1953
  - Wh-Z (Folder 43)
    - Wheeler, John P., 1953
    - Wherry, Kenneth S., 1950
    - White, Compton I., 1950
    - White, William C., 1951
    - Who’s Who in America, 1945
    - Wilfong, R. G., 1953
    - William Jewell College, 1951
    - Williams, J. D., 1950, 1952
    - Wilson, Hugh, 1948
    - H. W. Wilson Company, 1949
    - University of Wisconsin Press, 1971
    - Wisdom Hall of Fame, 1970 Enc.
    - Wood, Harold S., 1949-1953
    - World Council of Churches, 1952-1953
    - Wormuth, Francis D., 1953
    - Yale Law Journal, 1949
    - Yale Review, 1951
    - Yale University, 1945-1953 Enc.
    - Ylvisaker, Paul N., 1953
    - Young Adult Study, 1953 Enc.
    - Zasloff, Joseph, 1953
    - Zucker, Eugene, 1954
    - Unidentified Correspondence, 1948, 1951
    - Condolence letter to Mrs. Florence Schattschneider from Philip B. Brown, chairman of the Board of Trustees, Wesleyan University, 1971.
- Series 2. Writings and Speeches
  - After a Lifetime of Teaching My Greatest Regret is..., notes and corrected speech typescript, circa early 1960s (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Government and the Pursuit of Happiness, NBC Television Series Program Schedule and Transcripts, 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Interview Questions and Schattschneider's opening and closing remarks, typescripts, 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Interview script cards
    - Sherman Adams, 1957 (Folder 4)
    - Stephen K. Bailey, 1957 (Folder 5)
    - Julian Hartt, 1957 (Folder 6)
    - Frederick C. Mosher, 1957 (Folder 7)
    - Richard Newstadt, 1957 (Folder 8)
    - Richard Nixon, 1957 (Folder 9)
    - Ray Sherer, 1957 (Folder 10)
  - The American Party System, typescript (16 p.), undated (Folder 11)
  - The American Party System and National Security Policy, Address at the National War College, October 31, 1958, typescripts, 1958 (Folder 12)
  - Break Down the Departmental Walls, speech typescript (4 p.) and notes, circa 1953 (Folder 13)
  - Competing Theories of Party Organization..., corrected typescript (43 p.), undated (Folder 14)
  - Address to the Conference on Preparing College Men and Women for Politics, March 14, 1953, typescript (8 p.) (Folder 15)
  - Constitutional History of Connecticut, Connecticut League of Women Voters States Convention Presentation, typescript (3 p.), May 1946 (Folder 16)
  - Mim Daddario, tribute typescript (2 p.), 1971 (Folder 17)
  - Democracy, corrected manuscript (7 p.), circa 1960s (Folder 18)
  - Democracy is the Managing of Conflicts, typescript (2 p.), undated (Folder 19)
  - Domestic Politics and the Cold War, typescript (9 p.) and notes, ca. 1950s (Folder 20)
  - Equilibrium and Change in American Politics, typescript (11 p.), circa 1957-1958 (Folder 21)
  - The Great American Experiment [unpublished book]
    - Book outline, typescripts and notes, circa 1940s-50s (Folder 22)
    - Chapters, typescripts, circa 1940s-50s (Folder 23)
  - A Guide to the Study of Public Affairs
    - Chapter 3 - How to Study a Pressure Group, corrected typescript, 1951-1952 (Folder 24)
    - Photos and Illustrations, 1951-1952 (Folder 25)
    - Illustration negatives, 1951-1952 (Folder 26)
  - Intensity, Visibility, Direction and Scope, typescript (9 p.), 1957 (Folder 27)
  - Local Community Surveys as Cooperative Projects for Medium Sized Cities, typescript (4 p.), circa 1950s (Folder 28)
  - Local Government Survey - Description of a Laboratory Practice, corrected typescript (33 p.), circa 1950s (Folder 29)
  - My First Course in Political Science - 1911, draft (12 p.) and notes, undated (Folder 30)
  - The Nationalization of American Politics, corrected typescript (24 p.), undated (Folder 31)
  - Party Conflict, corrected typescripts (8 p.), undated (Folder 32)
  - Party Government
    - Printer's Proof, corrected (2 folders), 1941-1942 (Folder 33-34)
    - Corrected page proofs, 1940-1941 (Folder 35)
    - Page Proofs, 1940-1941 (Folder 36)
  - Political Action Committees and Party Organization, notes and drafts, circa 1953 (Folder 37)
  - Political Organization in the United States, typescript (4 p.), undated (Folder 38)
  - Political Parties and Democracy, corrected typescripts (2 folders), 1964 (Folder 39-40)
  - Political Parties Versus Pressure Groups, corrected typescript (7 p.) and drafts, undated (Folder 41)
  - Political Strategy, corrected typescripts, notes and drafts (34 p.), undated (Folder 42)
  - Politicians and Bankers, article in Motive supplement, October 1962 (Folder 43)
    See also same article in Christianity and Society 17, ii, Spring 1953.
  - Politicians and Power, corrected typescripts (16 p.), undated (Folder 44)
  - Politics as a Test of Strength, typescript (1 p.), undated (Folder 45)
  - Pressure Groups and Party Government, corrected typescript (204 p.) (Folder 46)
  - Pressure Groups Versus Political Parties, typescript (14 p.), undated (Folder 47)
  - The Self Educating Student, address to the New England Conference of the United States National Student Association, April 18, 1958, typescript (6 p.), 1958 (Folder 48)
  - The Semi-Sovereign People
    See also Oversized, Box 12
    - Early draft portions, corrected typescript, circa 1960 (Folder 49)
    - Chapter 2: Scope and Bias of the Political System, Pressure Politics, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts, circa 1960 (Folder 50)
    - Chapter 2: Scope and Bias of the Political System, Pressure Politics - Interests, Theory of, notes, circa 1960 (Folder 51)
    - Notes and early drafts of political parties and election results, circa 1960 (Folder 52)
    - Review in the New Republic, 1961 (Folder 53)
  - The Study of Government in the Liberal Arts College, typescript (16 p.), circa 1945-1946 (Folder 54)
  - The Surrender of Congressional Power to the President as Found in Tariff and Treaty Legislation, term paper typescript (12 p.), 1926 (Folder 55)
  - Two Hundred Million Americans in Search of a Government
    See also Oversized, Box 12.
    - Uncorrected typescript, 1968-1969 (Folder 56)
    - Corrected typescript, 1969-70 (Folder 57)
    - Author's Duplicate Pages, corrected typescript, 1969 (Folder 58)
    - Early notes and drafts (3 folders), circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Table of Contents and Introduction, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts, 1969 (Folder 4)
    - Chapter 1: What are We Looking For?, notes, drafts, and corrected typescripts (5 folders), 1969 (Folder 5-9)
    - Chapter 2: Why do People Make Miscalculations about Government?, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts (2 folders), 1969 (Folder 10-11)
    - Chapter 3: Democracy as a Moral System, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts, 1969 (Folder 12)
    - Chapter 4: Democracy as a Form of Government, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts (3 folders), 1969 (Folder 13-15)
    - Chapter 5: Why is a Generation the Proper Period of Time for the Study of Politics?, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts (2 folders), 1969 (Folder 16-17)
    - Chapter 6: Some Political Words, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts (2 folders), 1969 (Folder 18-19)
    - Chapter 7: Some Nongovernmental Thoughts About the Future of Government, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts, 1969 (Folder 20)
    - Appendix, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts, 1969 (Folder 21)
  - What is Good Teaching?, Address to the Conference on Preparing College Men and Women for Politics, corrected typescript (43 p.), 1953 (Folder 22)
  - What is Politics About?, notes and drafts, undated (Folder 23)
  - Connecticut Democratic Party, untitled corrected typescripts (3 p.), circa 1944-1945 (Folder 24)
  - "Four basic considerations provide the setting for a discussion of the meaning of the "responsible society" for political life in America," untitled typescript (11 p.), undated (Folder 25)
  - Interview transcript. Yale Interprets the News, November 1, 1953 (4 p.), 1953 (Folder 26)
  - The Meaning of Party Conflict, untitled corrected typescript (7 p.), undated (Folder 27)
  - Textbook on Political Parties, notes and drafts (2 folders), undated (Folder 28-29)
    Includes Government 8 Final Exam, June 1947 (Wesleyan) on verso of note leaf.
  - Two-Party System, untitled speech typescript (16 p.), undated (Folder 30)
  - Warfare and Democracy, untitled corrected speech typescript and notes (9 p.), ca. 1941- 45 (Folder 31)
  - What is the Meaning of Political Strategy?, untitled typescript (16 p.), undated (Folder 32)
  - Unpublished Book on American government and its place in the world political system. At one time titled The Resolution of Conflict - An Explanation of American Government
    - A New Kind of Book in American Government, preliminary outline, drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 33)
    - Chapter outlines, drafts (2 folders), undated (Folder 34-35)
    - Early drafts (2 folders), circa 1969 (Folder 36-37)
    - American Government, notes, drafts and corrected typescripts (4 folders), circa 1969 (Folder 38-41)
    - Corrected typescripts (3 folders), ca. 1970-1971 (Box 4, Folder 1-3)
    - Titles, notes and clippings, circa 1969 (Folder 4)
- Series 3. Teaching, Wesleyan Government Department, Student Papers.
  - Teaching
    - American Government, draft list of class books and assignments, circa 1930s-1940s (Folder 5)
    - Government 8, Syllabi, assignments and exams, 1939-1946 (Folder 6)
    - Government I 1948-49, Syllabus and handouts, 1948 (Folder 7)
      Includes Political Planning and Party Reconstruction, typescript, 28 p.
    - Government 58, Interviewing guidelines, circa 1950s (Folder 8)
    - Federal Loyalty Program, Wesleyan class projects, typescripts, drafts and correspondence, 1952-1953 (Folder 9)
    - Notebooks [2] containing lecture and class notes, 1952-1953 (Folder 10)
    - Government 2 syllabus, 1953 (Folder 11)
    - Political Science 531 - American Politics, bibliography and gradebook, after 1954 (Folder 12)
      Possibly from course at Michigan State University; not a Wesleyan class.
    - Government 374 class list, Fall 1967 (Folder 13)
    - Government 374 Fall 1968, syllabus, notes, class list and grades, 1968-1969 (Folder 14)
    - Govs 203, Fall 1969 (Folder 15)
    - Govs 204 and 300, Spring 1970 (Folder 16)
    - Lecture notes to introductory government class, undated (Folder 17)
    - Why Do We Study Government?, lecture notes, undated (Folder 18)
  - Wesleyan Government Department
    - Application For a Grant to Finance a Special Course in Practical Politics to be Given at Wesleyan Beginning February 1954, Falk Foundation, typescript, 1953 (Folder 19)
    - Government department and faculty memos, 1946, 1965, 1968 (Folder 20)
    - Study Committee memo containing outline of Wesleyan/Yale book on Christian Ethics and Public Policy, 1955 (Folder 21)
    - Eagleton Foundation Inter-University Casebook Committee, minutes and correspondence, 1956 (Folder 22)
  - Student Papers
    - Hogan, Matthew J., Analysis of 1946 city election in Hartford, CT, Government 7 paper, 1947 (Folder 23)
    - Lifset, Edward W., A Study of the Second Congressional District in Connecticut, 1951, circa 1951-1953 (Folder 24)
    - Epstein, David W., Government 58s Summer Work Program weekly report, June 21, 1957 (Folder 25)
    - Sharkansky, Ira S., A Straining Giant, 1960 (Folder 26)
    - Individual Community Analyses, January 1956 - May 1963
      Bound student papers from Government Department Seminar in Practical Politics (Gov. 57, 58, 58s, 59).
      - Brubaker, George, class of 1964. Lancaster PA. Undated. Includes photos. (Folder 27)
      - Camp, Herbert, class of 1957. New Britain CT, 1956. (Folder 28)
      - Carr, Louis, class of 1962. Weston and Falmouth MA, November 1961. (Folder 29)
      - Corrodi, John Theron Jr., class of 1957. Columbus OH, undated (Folder 30)
      - Craig, Barry G., class of 1963. East and West Hartford CT, May 1963. (Folder 31)
      - Ellis, Harry A., class of 1959. Rome GA, (2 folders), 1958. Includes photos. (Folder 32-33)
      - Emmett, Jack S., class of 1963. Uxbridge and Blackstone, MA, January 1963. Includes photos.. (Folder 34)
      - Frost, Fredric W., class of 1956. New Castle, NY. Inc. photos. undated (Folder 35)
      - Gay, Phineas Ellis Jr., class of 1956. Branford, CT, January 1956. Includes photos. (Folder 36)
      - Halgren, Jack, class of 1962. Newport Beach and Costa Mesa CA. n.d. (Folder 37)
      - Hazlehurst, John, class of 1962. Colorado Springs Co. and Broadmoor, January 1962. (Folder 38)
      - King, Dennis B., class of 1956. Redwood City, CA, January 1956. 1 volume and 1 folder. Includes photos. (Box 5)
      - La Brie, Lawrence James, class of 1956. Rye, NY, 1955-1956. Includes photos.
      - Lacava, Anthony, class of 1958. Waterbury, CT. undated
      - Lockwood, Timothy, class of 1957. Utica, NY. undated
      - McCann, Walter J. Jr., class of 1959. Plymouth, MA. Includes photos. Undated
      - McCarron, John R., class of 1962. Philadelphia, PA, January 1962.
      - McClellan, B. Edward, class of 1961. Huntington, WV and Memphis, TN. Includes photos. Undated
      - Parkin, John F., class of 1957. Suffolk County, NY, January 1957.
      - Pisetsky, Marvin S., class of 1956. Hartford, CT. undated
      - Teaford, H. Joel, class of 1962. Union City IN-OH and Reynoldsburg OH, January 1962.
      - Thomas, Allen C., class of 1961. Troy, NY. Includes photos, undated
      - Tompkins, Richard B., class of 1958. Norristown PA, January 1958. Includes photos. Undated
      - Toner, Roger, class of 1957. Montclair, NJ. Undated
      - Townsend, Robert I. Jr., class of 1962. White Plains and New Rochelle NY, January 1962.
      - Vermilya, Clifford R., class of 1959. Stratford, CT, February 1958.
      - Walker, George, class of 1962. Los Alamos and Santa Fe, NM, January 1962.
      - Willig, Richard L., class of 1962. Beverly Hills and Culver City, CA, January 1962.
- Series 4. Subject Files
  - Subject files for Two Hundred Million Americans in Search of a Government.
    - Bias (in Government), notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Change, notes and clippings, circa 1960-1967 (Folder 2)
    - Conflict, notes, undated (Folder 3)
    - Criticisms of Government, notes, circa 1960s (Folder 4)
    - Democracy, notes and drafts (2 folders), circa 1960s (Folder 5-6)
    - Elections and Party Organization, notes and clippings, circa 1962 (Folder 7)
    - The Future of Government, notes and clippings, circa 1957-1964 (Folder 8)
    - Government, notes and clippings, circa 1967-1968 (Folder 9)
    - Government and Business, notes and drafts, circa 1960s (Folder 10)
    - Highways, notes and clippings, circa 1968 (Folder 11)
    - Involvement (Our Involvement in Government), notes and drafts, circa 1960s (Folder 12)
    - Money, notes, undated (Folder 13)
    - Presidency, notes and clippings, 1968 (Folder 14)
    - Public Interest, notes, circa 1960s (Folder 15)
    - Scope and Space, notes and clippings, ca. 1952-65 (Folder 16)
    - Time, notes and clippings, circa 1962 (Folder 17)
    - Time, Change, notes, clippings and drafts, circa 1962-1969 (Folder 18)
    - Where Do You Have a Right to Be?, notes and clippings, 1957-64 (Folder 19)
  - Subject files for unpublished book on American government and its place in the world political system.
    See also written drafts in Writings and Speeches series.
    - Acts not Encouraged; Words Avoided, notes, undated (Folder 20)
    - American Government as a Contentious Proceeding, notes, drafts and clippings (3 folders), circa 1967-1970 (Folder 21-23)
    - Attacks on the Government, notes, undated (Folder 24)
    - Basic Assumptions, notes and clippings, circa 1969 (Folder 25)
    - British Origins [of U.S. government], notes and drafts (2 folders), circa 1969 (Folder 26-27)
    - Change, notes and clippings, 1957-circa 1963 (Folder 28)
    - Congress, notes and clippings, circa 1961 (Folder 29)
    - Congress: Series of Statutes; Congress Continues the Conflicts-Subject to Review, notes, undated (Folder 30)
    - The Complex, notes, drafts and clippings (2 folders), circa 1969 (Folder 31-32)
    - Consensus - Unanimity, notes, circa 1969 (Folder 33)
    - Courts and Questions, notes, undated (Folder 34)
    - Delay vs. Obstruction, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 35)
    - Democracy, notes, drafts and clippings (2 folders of 4), 1968-1970 (Folder 36-37)
    - Democracy, notes, drafts and clippings (2 folders of 4), 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - The Endless Discussion, notes and clippings, circa 1969-1970 (Folder 3)
    - The Endless Discussion, notes, drafts and clippings, 1969-1970 (Folder 4)
    - Equality, Consistency, Precedent, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 5)
    - Expansion of the American Community, notes, undated (Folder 6)
    - Foolish Projects, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 7)
    - The Function of the Upper Classes, notes, circa 1969 (Folder 8)
    - The Game of Politics, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 9)
    - General Consent, notes and clippings (2 folders), circa 1966-1970 (Folder 10-11)
    - Government and Business, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 12)
    - Government by Consent of the Losers/Majority Rule and Consent, notes and clippings, 1969-1970 (Folder 13)
    - A Government of Moderation, notes, drafts and clippings, circa 1969-1970 (Folder 14)
    - Government-making Words, drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 15)
    - The High Court of Congress, notes and clippings, ca. 1969 (Folder 16)
    - The History of Government, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 17)
    - How to Make a Nation, notes, undated (Folder 18)
    - Indirection/How Power is Exercised, notes, drafts and clippings (2 folders), circa 1968-69 (Folder 19-20)
    - Jefferson on Democracy and Public Policy, notes and drafts, ca. 1969 (Folder 21)
    - Judicial Review, notes, undated (Folder 22)
    - Laud - Successful Policies - What is Success?, note and drafts, 1968-1969 (Folder 23)
    - Legislation, notes, undated (Folder 24)
    - Mobility, notes, drafts and clippings, 1968-1969 (Folder 25)
    - Note Cards, circa 1969 (Folder 26)
    - The Plebiscitary Presidency, notes, circa 1969 (Folder 27)
    - Political Parties, notes and clippings, circa 1967 (Folder 28)
      Includes untitled typescript, 8p.
    - Politics, Democracy, Consent, Resolution of Conflict, notes, drafts and clippings (2 folders), circa 1969-1970 (Folder 29-30)
    - Popular Interpretations of the Constitution, notes and drafts, circa 1969 (Folder 31)
    - Precedent and Confidence, notes, drafts and clippings, circa 1967-70 (Folder 32)
    - Presidency, notes, drafts, typescripts and clippings (4 folders), circa 1969 (Folder 33-36)
    - The Raft and the River, notes and clippings, n.d. (Folder 37)
    - The Raft and the River, notes and drafts, undated (Folder 38)
    - The Raft and the River- Democracy - Liberty and the Private Sector, notes, drafts and clippings, circa 1969-70 (Folder 39)
    - A Revolution?, notes, undated (Folder 40)
    - The Right to Complain, notes, drafts and clippings, 1965-1969 (Folder 41)
    - The Scrambled Test; Test Your Sense of History, notes, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Tentativeness of Public Policy, notes and clippings, circa 1969-1970 (Folder 2)
    - Transitions [in power], notes, drafts and clippings, 1968-1969 (Folder 3)
    - What Does the Budget Tell Us?, notes, undated (Folder 4)
    - Why an Extremist Has Never Been Elected President, notes, circa 1969 (Folder 5)
    - X-Factor, notes, circa 1969 (Folder 6)
  - Subject files, general
    - American Government, clippings (3 folders), 1960-1962 (Folder 7-9)
    - American Political Science Association, Committee on Political Parties, drafts, 1947 (Folder 10)
      Includes draft memos by Clarence Berdahl, interim reports, preliminary draft titled Outline for a Proposed Program for Party Responsibility, and typescripts by Schattschneider: Wartime Political Behavior, Some Suggestions for Regional Political Research, and Objectives in Research Concerning the Present Status of Political Parties in the United States.
    - Biographies, notes and drafts, undated (Folder 11)
    - Book Citations (45), index cards, undated (Folder 12)
    - Book titles, note cards, circa 1950s-60s (Folder 13)
    - Campaign Funds, clippings, 1930-1931 (Folder 14)
    - Campaign Funds (1930), Nye Committee, clippings, 1930 (Folder 15)
    - Campaigns - Conduct of, clippings (3 folders), 1944 (Folder 16-18)
    - Campaigns - Conduct of, Red Scare, clippings (3 folders), 1944 (Folder 19-21)
    - Citizenship Clearing House History, typescript, circa 1960s (Folder 22)